<document>
    <head>
<publisher>New York Times (1857-1922)</publisher>; 
<pubDate>Dec 24, 1905</pubDate>;ProQuest pg.8
<title>DANGERS OF DIRECT CURRENT</title>
<subtitle number="1"><persName xml:id="#Westinghouse">George Westinghouse</persName> Sees More Advantages inn His Alternating System.</subtitle>
</head>
    <body>
<p><persName xml:id="#Westinghouse">George Westinghouse</persName>, President of the Westinghouse Electric Company, in a let-warns the public of the destructive effect ter to The Railroad Gazette of last week of loose electric currents on all underground metallic work such as is employed in the Subway and in the <loc>New York Central</loc> and <loc>Pennsylvania</loc> tunner improvements and on the city gas and water pipes.</p>
<p>"It has been shown fully and completely," he says, "that the <current type="DC">direct current</current> is working all of the time in the destruction of some of the metallic structures, especially water and gas pipes, adjacent to electric conductors, which metallic structures invariably act as conductors for some of the currentescaping from the uninsulated rails forming part of the electric circuit in railroad operations."</p>
<p>He shows photographs of water pipes destroyed by electrolytic action from <current type="DC">direct current</current> circuits such as is carried by the third rail in use in the Subway and on the upper railroad about to be installed in the <loc>Park Avenue tunnel</loc>, and contends that the steel structural part of the <loc>New York City Subway</loc> will be so destroyed unless the <current type="AC">alternating current</current> is used, which he says has practically no destructive effect on metal pipes and structural steel.</p>
<p>In the same number of The Railroad Gazette he makes public certain correspondence with President Newman of the New York Central in which he asserts that high speed with heavy trains is economically possible only where the <current type="AC">alternating current</current> is used, and he believes that in the few substitutions so far made of <current type="DC">direct current</current>, third-rail electric motors for steam locomotives, the work will need to be done over again.</p>
    </body>
</document>
pp
