<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="projectSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<document>
    <head>
    <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <author>Author Not Specified</author>
            <title>May Pull Through</title>
            If not his company will probably be absorbed
            <encodingHistory>
                <work role="encoder">Jamie Downey</work>
                <work role="transcriber">Jamie Downey</work>
            </encodingHistory>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt> 
            <pubDate>1891-01-17</pubDate>
            <publisher>The Thomson-Houston Company [by Telegraph to the Herald]</publisher>
        </publicationStmt>
    </fileDesc>
    </head>
    <body>
       <p><loc>Pittsburg, Pa</loc>., <date xsd="1891-01-16"> Jan. 16, 1891</date>.--The latest guess at the probable outcome of the financial
        troubles of the <company name="Westinghouse">Westinghouse Electric Manurfacturing Company</company> is that under the terms "of
        consolidation" the <company name="Westinghouse">Westinghouse company</company> will be absorbed by its great Eastern rival, the
        <company name="Thomson-Houston">Thomson-Houston company</company>. Officials of the <company name="Westinghouse">Westinghouse company</company> will not talk of this, but it
        is known that the chief counsel for the <company name="Thomson-Houston">Thomson-Houston company</company> has been consultation for
        several days with representatives of the <company name="Westinghouse">Westinghouse</company> interests.</p>
        <p><persName ref="#Other">Henry W. Long</persName>, a leading
        broker and heavy holder of <company name="Westinghouse">Westinghouse</company> stock, said to-day he considered a receivership of
        the <company name="Westinghouse">Westinghouse company</company> or consolidation inevitable. He considers consolidation more likely
        to result in good for the stockholders than a receivership. </p>
        <p><persName ref="#Westinghouse">Mr. Westinghouse</persName> did not return
        to <loc>Pittsburg</loc> to-day, but wired that he still has strong hopes of placing enough of the
        preferred stock of his company to enable it to weather the storm. it is understood no new
        suits will be entered until <date xsd="1891-01-26">January 26</date>, the first return day. Creditors can gain nothing
        moving before, and the feeling.</p>
    </body>
</document>
